(upbeat music)
- Hello everyone and
welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
- My name is Catherine.
And today we've got
a very, very interesting
lesson for you all about
building your vocabulary.
So we're trying to describe a personality.
You're gonna learn tons of new words.
- Exactly.
And as you said, we're gonna
describe people's personality.
So not their physical attributes.
We're gonna concentrate on how they are
in personality-wise and stuff like that.
They're character.
- That's right.
- So let's take a listen
to today's dialogue
for the first time and we back in a moment
to talk about some of these great words.
(upbeat music)
- Okay class, settle down.
I have the results of your
individual personality tests.
I am going to hand
them out and if you'd like,
you can read them out
loud to the rest of the class.
- I'll read mine.
Okay, go ahead.
It says here that I am adventurous,
outgoing, and easy-going.
It says that I'm a little
superstitious and occasionally naive.
That's not true.
- Well, the test isn't 100% accurate.
Is that all it says?
- No.
It also says that I'm
open-minded with great
ambition, but that I can
also be reckless and clumsy.
This is stupid.
- Okay, anyone else wants to read theirs?
- Okay.
- It says that I'm an extroverted,
well-balanced person.
It says I am generous,
outspoken, and very diligent.
This is so true.
It also says that I am a
magnanimous, eloquent and daring.
This is totally me.
- Whatever.
These tests are baloney.
(upbeat music)
- All right, we're back.
So we're gonna divide this up into
language takeaway parts one and two.
So let's start with five key
words now on language takeaway.
- Language takeaway.
- The first adjective that
came up was adventurous
and outgoing, outgoing, that's a good one.
- Outgoing is a great one.
So you think of the word out.
That means moving out,
going out, outgoing means
someone is very comfortable
talking to strangers
or talking to people that
they don't know very well.
For example, my brother is very outgoing.
He loves meeting new people.
He loves starting
conversations with strangers.
- So the opposite would be shy.
- That's right. - That's the opposite.
Okay, so outgoing.
And then it also described this
person as being a little superstitious.
- Okay, superstitious is very interesting
because it's hard to describe since
everyone's superstitions are different.
In many cultures, there
are different superstitions.
So for example, in America, we
say that walking under a ladder
is bad luck or opening an
umbrella inside is bad luck.
So if you believe that
your actions will bring
you bad luck, you're
probably superstitious.
- Okay, very good.
So if you are superstitious,
you believe in superstitions.
- That's right.
So Marco, are you superstitious?
Do you think that black
cats bring bad luck?
- No, not at all.
No, no, interesting.
- All right, and this is
also an interesting word
a way to describe people who are
very believing a person that is naive.
- Okay, you said this already
naive means that someone
generally believes most
things that you tell them.
- Right.
- So if I told you Marco, hey,
did you know that it's
supposed to rain frogs tomorrow?
- No way, really.
- Yeah, really.
If Marco believes me, he's naive.
That means that probably
not gonna rain frogs tomorrow,
but he believes everything I say, so
he's a little bit naive or inexperienced.
- So naive is not really a bad
way of describing a person, is it?
- No, but it can be.
So you want to be careful.
Some people, if you say that
they're being naive, it's offensive.
So you have to be
careful when you say this.
- Okay, moving on, we also
had an interesting adjective
that described another
person and it was the reckless.
I can also be reckless.
- Reckless, okay.
So someone who is
reckless often does things
without thinking, sometimes
things that are dangerous.
For example, Marco, I
think that driving a car
without wearing your
seat belt is very reckless.
Okay, that means that you're
not thinking about safety.
- Right.
So a person that is reckless
is a kind of a synonym
of being a little bit
dangerous to be around.
- That's right.
Or someone who does things without thinking
about their consequences, their results.
Okay, and also along with reckless,
the test said that this person was clumsy.
- Oh, I love this word.
There was a very famous commercial
when I was growing up in
America on the television.
It was all about young
students at high school
who are clumsy and so
they should buy this special
folder for their school work to
help them 'cause they're so clumsy.
- And they're dropping
their papers and their books.
- Exactly, so someone who
is clumsy often falls down
or hits their head or
trips or drops their things.
If I drop something on the floor and break
it, my mother might say, you're so clumsy.
- You're a clumsy finger.
- You need more careful.
- Yeah, so clumsy is this insulting,
if you say, oh, you're so clumsy.
- No, it's not so bad.
There are worse things to say,
but if someone often drops things,
you can call them clumsy, or you can
also say, you're such a butter fingers.
- That means that your
fingers are like butter.
They're very slippery, you drop everything.
- Okay, so clumsy and reckless,
they are negative adjectives, right?
They're saying that you do things in wrong.
So it's not really a good
thing to be reckless or clumsy.
- No, it's not really a good thing.
These are not positive characteristics.
- Okay, good.
So we took a look at
those five, which are very
good about one of the
people that took the test.
Let's move on now to more language and more
adjectives on language takeaway part two.
- Language takeaway.
- All right, so in this
part, we're gonna take a
look at positive attributes
about a person, right?
They're all good things about someone.
- That's right, and this
first one is very good.
Extraverted, extraverted.
- A person that's extraverted.
- So a synonym of this word is outgoing.
- Okay.
- So it's pretty much the same thing.
- That's right, because
extra means going out, out.
So in this case, someone
who is extraverted often
meets new people, goes
out and does social things,
goes to the movies, goes out
with friends, meets strangers,
talks to strangers, again,
it's like being outgoing.
Someone who's comfortable with new people.
- And what about the opposite?
So we said that shy is
the opposite of outgoing.
What would be the opposite for extraverted?
- Extraverted's opposite is
introverted, intro means in, not out.
So that means someone who's very shy,
who is uncomfortable with new people.
- Okay, and well apart
from being extroverted,
the test also said that
this person is very diligent.
- Ooh, diligent is a great word.
This is a word you wanna hear
from your teachers and your bosses.
Okay, if someone says Marco,
you're very diligent at work.
- What does that mean?
- And you're very careful, you
always do things very thoroughly.
- And also quickly, right?
When you tell them to do
something, they do it immediately.
- That's right, so a
diligent worker always
does a good job and
does it in a timely manner.
- Okay, and moving on to our third
adjective, this one is kind of strange.
It kind of sounds like
monogamy, but it's magnanimous.
- Magnanimous, magnanimous.
- This is a great word.
We hear this a lot in the newspaper
or on TV about usually famous people.
He did something very magnanimous
or it was a magnanimous gesture.
This describes a person who does
things for the benefit of other people.
Someone who is thinking about the well-being
and the health and the lives of others.
- So it would be a person that likes
to share or a person that's not selfish.
- Right, so if you donate
half of your salary this month
to victims of an earthquake,
I would say Marco,
that's so magnanimous of
you, you're so magnanimous.
- Okay, awesome, and apart
from being magnanimous,
if a person is eloquent, I guess
that's also a positive attribute.
- Oh yeah, this is another really good one.
Someone who is eloquent
is a very good speaker.
Okay, this means that when they
talk, they sound very, very good.
- Okay.
- Someone who is eloquent uses big words,
but is also very good at
making other people listen.
- Okay.
- So it's usually about speaking.
So he's an eloquent speaker.
- That's right, so
someone who is eloquent
is fun or good or
interesting to listen to.
- Okay, and our last
description for personalities
and the way people are
is a person that's daring.
- Well, this can be a
good thing or a bad thing.
It depends on who you're talking about.
Because sometimes daring people are
also reckless, and this can be dangerous.
But sometimes someone who is
daring can be doing good things.
Like a daring business person might
take risks that other people don't take.
- Okay, so a person that's
daring, dares to take risks, right?
- You are very daring.
You, Mark, are daring because
recently you jumped out
of an airplane, right,
you did some sky diving.
So that would be considered daring.
- That's very daring,
I'm not daring like that
because I would never
jump out of an airplane.
- Right, okay, so we took a look at basically
10 key words here, a lot of adjectives,
but they're a great
way to describe yourself.
Maybe if you're at a job interview, they,
you know, sometimes a typical question is,
how would you describe yourself
in three, using three adjectives?
- I'm extroverted, I'm
diligent, and I'm open-minded.
- Yeah, that's awesome, see?
You sound really professional
when you say things.
- Keep it the job.
- Yeah.
- Exactly, so, and even if you took a look
at some of the negative
adjectives that we used,
it's also a typical job interview question
is like, what are your biggest faults?
So you can say, well, maybe
I am superstitious and naive.
- Right.
- You wouldn't want to say
that at the end of job interview.
But I mean, maybe, I don't know, maybe,
because you have to say something, right?
- You do, but I would say
sometimes I'm a bit too daring
or sometimes I take things personally, so
well, we can talk about that another time,
but I think for now, it'd be good if we
listen to today's dialogue one more time
and really got a good sense
of how to use these words.
(upbeat music)
- Okay, class, settle down.
I have the results of your
individual personality tests.
I am going to hand
them out and if you'd like,
you can read them out
loud to the rest of the class.
- I'll read mine.
- Okay, go ahead. It says here that I
am adventurous, outgoing and easygoing.
It says that I'm a little
superstitious and occasionally naive.
- That's not true.
- Well, the test isn't 100% accurate.
Is that all it says?
- No, it also says that I'm
open-minded with great
ambition but that I can
also be reckless and clumsy.
This is stupid.
- Okay.
- Anyone else wants to read theirs?
- I'll go. It says that I'm an
extroverted, well-balanced person.
It says I am generous,
outspoken and very diligent.
This is so true.
It also says that I am a
magnanimous, eloquent and daring.
This is totally me.
- Whatever, these tests are baloney.
(upbeat music)
- All right, we're back.
So now going into descriptions.
What are three adjectives
that you would use
to describe someone
that you hate the most?
So going back to describing
people, how would you describe
one of the main things that
really irritate you about someone?
Maybe if they are clumsy,
it really bothers you that people
are clumsy or reckless, maybe.
- Ah, I see what you're saying.
Well, I really like extroverted
hardworking people
but in English we
have a word to describe
someone who is too
extroverted, too hardworking.
Now we call this person a type
A personality, type A, the letter A.
And this means someone
who works very, very hard,
who is very serious, but
who's always anxious,
always needs to get
things done, right?
And so these people can
be very hard to work with
because they're controlling
and they're never calm.
- So they're not easy going?
- No, they're not easy going.
They always want to
do what they want to do.
They're usually not very good listeners.
And so this type A personality is something
that I would say, I'm
not a big fan of at work
or even when we're going
out because with friends,
it's hard to be around someone
who always has to control you.
- This is very interesting
and I'm sure our listeners
have a lot of different
ways to describe
things that irritate them,
maybe about people,
or maybe attributes that they
really admire about someone.
- That's right.
- To give everybody a
little bit of homework today,
go home or if you're
at home, look up a word
in the dictionary that describes yourself
and adjective to describe yourself.
I think this is a really good
homework assignment
because you'll be
improving your vocabulary
and then put it on our
website, EnglishPod.
com, let us know more about you.
- Okay, we'll see everyone there.
- Bye everyone. - Bye.
(upbeat music)
[BLANK_AUDIO]